

8152 Cool Ridge Drive SW, Byron Center, Mi 49315

□ 708-689-7128 | ☑ oneilljohnpaul36@gmail.com | 🄏 oneilljp.github.io | 🖸 oneilljp

Summary_

Fourth Year Computer Science student at the University of Michigan. 2.5 years of programming coursework with a record of success and a desire to learn more. Long history of proven servant leadership skills, with a passion for open source software and improving the accessibility of technology and computer science education to underrepresented communities.

Projects_

RustMe

RUST May 2021 - Auq. 2021

· Created a cross-platform terminal user interface to act as an alternative to the GroupMe web client.

Algovisualizer

JavaScript, HTML Canvas

May 2020 - Aug. 2020

• Created a website that visualizes different pathfinding and maze generation algorithms on a two-dimensional grid in order for individuals to have a visual aide to assist in learning these algorithms.

Technical Skills ___

LanguagesC++, C, Rust, Python, Node.js,Back-endFlask, SQLite, REST APIFront-endReact, HTML5, css,

Operating Systems Linux, Windows, Mac

Version Control Git

Education

University of Michigan B. S. COMPUTER SCIENCE - GPA: 3.67

Ann Arbor, MI

Anticipated Graduation: May 2022

Relevant Coursework:

- EECS 281: Data Structures and Algorithms
- EECS 370: Computer Organization
- EECS 376: Foundations of Computer Science
- EECS 485: Websystems
- EECS 493: User Interface Development (Currently Enrolled)
- EECS 494: Introduction to Game Development (Currently Enrolled)

Work Experience

University of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI

INSTRUCTOR'S AIDE

August 2021 - Present

- · Developed an advanced project specification to introduce students to basic interactions with public API's with various languages.
- Hosted weekly office hours to assist students with in-class work and to grade project progress while creating an inclusive environment to allow students to succeed.

University of Michigan Ann Arbor, Mi

RESSTAFF COORDINATOR

August 2021 - Present

- Served as a role model and mentor for all South Quadrangle Resstaff members with respect to community development, programming, and promoting diversity, equity, and inclusion.
- Facilitated dialogue between Resstaff members, Hall Directors, and Community Center Managers revolving around specific needs of the building community.
- Assisted Hall Directors in facilitating scheduling for overnight duty shifts, and served as an advisor to the building's hall council.

Human-Computer Interaction Institute at Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

DECIMAL LEARNING GAME PROGRAMMER

June 2021 - August 2021

- Wrote and revised code with a team of interns to modify an existing decimal number learning game, Decimal Point, in order to prepare it for new classroom studies.
- Utilized JavaScript to implement animations and "mindfulness interventions" to assist students who make repeated mistakes while playing the game.

1Cademy Ann Arbor, MI

OBJECT-ORIENTED PROGRAMMING COMMUNITY CO-LEADER

January 2021 - Present

- Lead a team of interns in aggregating knowledge about Object-Oriented Programming concepts and languages on the large-scale platform 1Cademy, with a focus on organizing information in nodes through prerequisite linking.
- Coordinated interns in assessing the specific needs of other communities on the 1Cademy platform, and in implementing programming solutions to alleviate said needs in smaller project teams.

University of Michigan Ann Arbor, MI

RESIDENTIAL ADVISOR

August 2020 - Present

- Built community in the South Quadrangle Residence hall by participating in and encouraging casual social interaction, planning and implementing social programming, and demonstrating consistent availability and accessibility to residents.
- Supported the needs of residents through intentional interactions and virtual activities, connecting residents to campus resources, and responding to crisis situations.